Burma
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Burma
2.1.3.1.1.6
Marist College
MMM
MMM
MMM
  Box 1500
- Burma, 2.1.3.1.1.6
  - Burma, 1 (Box 1500)
    - Shwedagon Pagoda, sunset, 1
  - Burma, 2 (Box 1500)
    - Shwedagon Pagoda, four palm trees and small boy, 1
  - Burma, 3 (Box 1500)
    - Entrance to Shwedagon Pagoda, front view, 1
  - Burma, 4 (Box 1500)
    - Group of small pagodas at base of Shwedagon Pagoda, corner of carved pagoda on left, 1
  - Burma, 5 (Box 1500)
    - Enormous Buddha, close-up, Lowell Thomas in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 6 (Box 1500)
    - Priest, begging bowl, servant holding fan, 1
  - Burma, 7 (Box 1500)
    - Chinese Palace as seen through gateway, 1
  - Burma, 8 (Box 1500)
    - Chinese Palace from lake, 1
  - Burma, 9 (Box 1500)
    - Shwesandaw temples on platform, priest in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 10 (Box 1500)
    - Close-up of oil derricks, two men in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 11 (Box 1500)
    - Mahabodhi Temple, 1
  - Burma, 12 (Box 1500)
    - Fat woman and baby, 1
  - Burma, 13 (Box 1500)
    - Buddha, Ganugan, 1
  - Burma, 14 (Box 1500)
    - Two boats with one sail, side view, 1
  - Burma, 15 (Box 1500)
    - Close-up of stern of carved boat, 1
  - Burma, 16 (Box 1500)
    - Small white pagoda with lights at night, 1
  - Burma, 17 (Box 1500)
    - Festival under palm trees at foot of Mandalay Hill, 1
  - Burma, 18 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Mandalay from hill, 1
    - Verso: View from Mandalay Hill - Hill has always been covered with shrines but of little importance. A pungyi now called "the Hermit Priest" because he won't live in a Kyaung, went up there some 10 yrs ago and was the founder of their largest shrines on the hill and also has built covered passages approaching hill from 3 sides
  - Burma, 19 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Irrawaddy from hill, 1
    - Verso: Panorama of Irrawaddy from Mandalay Hill looking west to the river. In distance on right is the Mingun Bell
  - Burma, 20 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Kuthodaw Pagodas, 1
    - Verso: Panorama of Kuthodaw Pagoda (on left). Built by Mindon Min. There are 730 small ones around large central one. Atumashi (or incomparable) Pagoda now under construction by the Hermit Priest with public subscriptions
  - Burma, 21 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Kuthodaw Pagodas, 1
  - Burma, 22 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Kuthodaw Pagodas, nearer view, 1
    - Verso: I counted all of them, and it took six hours for Mr. Noyce to do this.
  - Burma, 23 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Kuthodaw Pagodas, 1
  - Burma, 24 (Box 1500)
    - Panorama of Atumashi Pagodas, 1
    - Verso: Atumashi Pagodas. Incomparable Pagoda (original built Mindon burned down in 1892, probably by Burmans. In the brow of the Buddah which was an image of brick works, was a 40 Karat diamond.) Diamond disappeared.
  - Burma, 25 (Box 1500)
    - Close-up of Atumashi Pagoda, person with umbrella in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 26 (Box 1500)
    - Burman reading scripture written on rock, 1
  - Burma, 27 (Box 1500)
    - Kyauk Taw Gyi Pagoda and moat from Mandalay Hill, 1
    - Verso: Kyauk Taw Gyi Pagoda (on right). See page 5 of Noyce Guide book, contains huge sitting Buddha carved out of single block of marble. Completed in 1866. Sculptured by order of King Mindon
  - Burma, 28 (Box 1500)
    - Mandalay Hill and East side of moat, 1
  - Burma, 29 (Box 1500)
    - Mandalay Hill and East side of moat, distant view, 1
  - Burma, 30 (Box 1500)
    - South side of moat, 1
  - Burma, 31 (Box 1500)
    - West side of moat, 1
    - Verso: Broken bridge in distance known as the Setshin Bridge and was entrance to the Queen's throne. Queen had hers on west and King on east on the "Lion Throne." Queen's throne was the "Lily Throne" emblymatic of beauty and purity. The lily can't be painted.
  - Burma, 32 (Box 1500)
    - South side of moat, sunset, 1
  - Burma, 33 (Box 1500)
    - South side of moat, sunset, 1
    - Verso: Moat originally 25 ft. deep and 100 ft. wide. Was once covered with large pink lotus lilies. After annexation in 1885 the British military authorities destroyed the lotus to prevent malaria. They haven't succeeded yet. Some lotus left. They keep destroying plants over and over. Roots, or suckers, are imbedded in ground and only way to drive out the lotus is to dry moat absolutely. Malaria is not bad here today though. Burmese love the lotus roots as vegetable food. Slightly similar in taste to turnip. Moat and walls were built by town ministers under Mindon. Each man had his own portion. This done to produce spirit of rivalry. Mindon impressed people into the work.
  - Burma, 34 (Box 1500)
    - East gate, 1
  - Burma, 35 (Box 1500)
    - South gate, 1
  - Burma, 36 (Box 1500)
    - South gate with water lilies, 1
  - Burma, 37 (Box 1500)
    - South gate, coolie with petrol tins in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 38 (Box 1500)
    - West gate, 1
    - Verso: All funerals and embassies passed thru here
  - Burma, 39 (Box 1500)
    - Nan Oo Pagoda, 1
    - Verso: To the east of the palace. Built by Mindon in 1857. There is always a pagoda to the east of every royal palace and facing the palace. On the north side there must also be a capinile or watch tower. Must be built simultaneously. All three must be finished at the same hour all at a given signal in the presence of the reigning king. Mr. H. C. Noyce says Col. Sladan's butler got drunk and went up in pagoda and kicked up a big row and he had to arrest him.
  - Burma, 40 (Box 1500)
    - Royal Palace from the East, 1
    - Verso: Royal palace from East, entrance to throne room. This palace was where audiences were held. Was built by Mindon. It was in this palace that Thebaw surrendered. Col. Sladan, who had been political resident in Mandalay, entered before troops. Mindon Min built a church and school for the church of Eng. for Dr. Marlas and sent the princes there including Thebaw. King and Queen Thebaw and Supyalat seldom ever left palace. Queen only went out 3 times. Afraid of assassins.
  - Burma, 41 (Box 1500)
    - Royal Palace from the East with troops in the foreground, 1
    - Verso: Eastern view of Royal Palace. Built of teals from the Shiveli forest in the Katha district where the finest teak comes from. Roofed with corrugated iron. British government has put in new foundations of concrete but lightning or earthquake might bring it down. Not a big earthquake here since 1839 which split the great Mingun Pagoda. It is one of the finest symmetrical buildings in Burma. Rises very gracefully from base. For carving the Queen's monastery built by Supyalat is finest example of carving altho not so symmetrical. In 1885 monastery was [?] of gold.
  - Burma, 42 (Box 1500)
    - Royal Palace from the East, distant view, 1
    - Verso: These cannon were presented by the French government to the Burmese government in days of King Pagan Min (the famous cock fighter whose capital was Amurapura.) He was defeated by his younger bro. Mindon who brought them to Mandalay. Mindon, after defeating his bro., treated him with great respect and enabled him to live royally to his death. Mindon was greatest of late Burman rulers. To please Queen Victoria he encouraged Christianity and built Christ Church. No war between Burma and Britain in his day. He sent an embassy to London to tell Queen Victoria he had done this meritorious act on her behalf. In return the Queen sent out a marble fount for Baptismal purposes which stands in the church today.
  - Burma, 43 (Box 1500)
    - Three tombs, branches above, 1
  - Burma, 44 (Box 1500)
    - Three tombs, no branches above, 1
    - Verso: Central tomb is where King Mindon was buried. Tomb on right is Queen Ain ByerMahyin, mother of Thebaw. (Owner of the White House) Tomb on left is where Queen Sinbyoo May Yin, (which means owner of a white elephant), mother of Supyalat. She was the intriguer and responsible for all the massacres in Oct. 1879, including 50 or 60 of the royal house. Supyalat sided with her mother but was only about 17 yrs. old although queen at the time. All of Thebaw's step bros. wanted to be king so it was done in defense of throne.
  - Burma, 45 (Box 1500)
    - Thebaw Kyaung with wife of Ou Chit Pwe dancing, Lowell Thomas with pith helmet, umbrella and cane, 1
    - Verso: King Thebaw's Kyaung- built by Mindon and where his son Thebaw rec'd his theological training. He was there until he was selected for the throne. It was done by lot but there was trickery on part of Supyalat's mother and she worked things so that he was the lucky man. He was not the eldest son and not even the son of the favorite queen. Thebaw was about 21 when he became king. Before then he was unknown. He was a handsome Burman, with round face, heavy mustache, and very heavy set. Not much intelligence doing. He let his mother in law and wife run things. Supyalat overrode king's ministers. There was talk among the ministers of Thebaw being too young and weak. Supyalat heard of this and put out all the ministers but one and he was the Prince minister who agreed to kneel before her golden foot. But he was the only high Burman official who tried to prevent the 3rd Burmese war. He had been to Eng. and knew Eng's power but others wouldn't listen. British gave him a pension until he died. Thebaw in monastery 2 or 3 years. British used it as a church of England for troops. Now going to ruin which is most unfortunate.
  - Burma, 46 (Box 1500)
    - Thebaw Kyaung with wife of Ou Chit Pwe dancing, Lowell Thomas with pith helmet, umbrella and cane, 1
  - Burma, 47 (Box 1500)
    - Thebaw Kyaung with wife of Ou Chit Pwe dancing, Lowell Thomas with pith helmet, umbrella and cane, 1
  - Burma, 48 (Box 1500)
    - Thebaw Kyaung with wife of Ou Chit Pwe dancing, 1
  - Burma, 49 (Box 1500)
    - Thebaw Kyaung with wife of Ou Chit Pwe dancing, 1
  - Burma, 50 (Box 1500)
    - Arakan Pagoda, entrance, 1
  - Burma, 51 (Box 1500)
    - Arakan Pagoda, three men in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 52 (Box 1500)
    - Arakan Pagoda and turtle pool, 1
  - Burma, 53 (Box 1500)
    - Arakan Pagoda from housetop, 1
  - Burma, 54 (Box 1500)
    - Arakan Pagoda from turtle pool, 1
    - Verso: The great image of Buddah in Akyab was taken by force from the Arakonese and brought to Mandalay, in 1784, although the town of Mandalay was not in existence in those days.
  - Burma, 55 (Box 1500)
    - Princess and kneeling servant, 1
  - Burma, 56 (Box 1500)
    - Princess with cheroot, close-up, 1
  - Burma, 57 (Box 1500)
    - Mingun Bell, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas with back to camera, woman squatting and man at right, 1
  - Burma, 58 (Box 1500)
    - Temple containing Mingun Bell, 1
  - Burma, 59 (Box 1500)
    - Fantastic shaped pagoda at Mingun, 1
  - Burma, 60 (Box 1500)
    - Sagaing Festival, woman holding small boy with cap, 1
  - Burma, 61 (Box 1500)
    - Sagaing Festival, woman with cheroot in mouth and child holding a plate, 1
  - Burma, 62 (Box 1500)
    - Sagaing girl with cheroot in mouth, 1
  - Burma, 63 (Box 1500)
    - Sagaing girl with wreath on head, other child in background, 1
  - Burma, 64 (Box 1500)
    - Sagaing, three children wearing wreaths, 1
  - Burma, 65 (Box 1500)
    - Woman with jumping jack, 1
  - Burma, 66 (Box 1500)
    - Gokteik bridge and train from below, 1
  - Burma, 67 (Box 1500)
    - Gokteik bridge without train, 1
  - Burma, 68 (Box 1500)
    - Gokteik Gorge from bridge, 1
  - Burma, 69 (Box 1500)
    - Sunset from Gokteik bridge, 1
  - Burma, 70 (Box 1500)
    - Entire Gokteik bridge, train in foreground, 1
  - Burma, 71 (Box 1500)
    - Raft of jars with steamer in distance, 1
  - Burma, 72 (Box 1500)
    - Thatched homes of pottery workers, man, woman, and child watching two men work, 1
  - Burma, 73 (Box 1500)
    - Two workmen turning jar, 1
  - Burma, 74 (Box 1500)
    - Woman selling small jar, 1
  - Burma, 75 (Box 1500)
    - Man scraping large jar with young boy looking on, 1
  Box 1501
- Burma, 2.1.3.1.1.6
  - Burma, 1 (Box 1501)
    - Girl with jar on shoulder, 1
  - Burma, 2 (Box 1501)
    - Girl with jar on shoulder, 1
  - Burma, 3 (Box 1501)
    - Four children around fire, 1
  - Burma, 4 (Box 1501)
    - R.I.M.S. "Bhama" in defile below Bhamo, group of people standing near steamer, 1
  - Burma, 5 (Box 1501)
    - R.I.M.S "Bhama", nearer view, 1
  - Burma, 6 (Box 1501)
    - Teak rafts lined along shore, 1
  - Burma, 7 (Box 1501)
    - Native sail boat carrying baskets, 1
  - Burma, 8 (Box 1501)
    - Poungyi (priest) teaching class (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 9 (Box 1501)
    - Poungyi (priest) teaching class under umbrella, 1
  - Burma, 10 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin battalion in military formation (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 11 (Box 1501)
    - Kachins and Chins in "Walking out kit" with their officers (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 12 (Box 1501)
    - Kachins and chins in "walking out kit" (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 13 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin troops and women making merry (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 14 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin men and women facing camera (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 15 (Box 1501)
    - Group of men and women, many with backs turned to camera (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 16 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin long house in hills (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 17 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin wearing Shan hat, hands on sword (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 18 (Box 1501)
    - Two Kachin Dah fighters posing (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 19 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin man with big hat, sword and bag (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 20 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin without hat, with fine bag and sword (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 21 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin in profile (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 22 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin playing shan drum (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 23 (Box 1501)
    - Portrait of sad faced Kachin, close-up (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 24 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin with broad sword in hand (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 25 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin place of sacrifice, distant view (Graphlex), 1
  - Burma, 26 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin place of sacrifice with man sitting on top, 1
  - Burma, 27 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin place of sacrifice, close-up, man standing by tree, 1
  - Burma, 28 (Box 1501)
    - Two Yaw Yen women and babies, 1
  - Burma, 29 (Box 1501)
    - One Yaw Yen woman and baby, 1
  - Burma, 30 (Box 1501)
    - Kachin woman, hand on tree, 1
  - Burma, 31 (Box 1501)
    - Fat Kachin woman arm on tree, 1
  - Burma, 32 (Box 1501)
    - Fat woman showing back of dress, 1
  - Burma, 33 (Box 1501)
    - Group of Chins in native war dress in semi-circle, 1
  - Burma, 34 (Box 1501)
    - Chin woman, hand on hip, 1
  - Burma, 35 (Box 1501)
    - Chin woman with face blackened to ears, side view, 1
  - Burma, 36 (Box 1501)
    - Chin chief in war garb, 1
  - Burma, 37 (Box 1501)
    - Sawbwa of Yanghhe and Lowell Thomas standing, 1
  - Burma, 38 (Box 1501)
    - Sawbwa and Mr. Brown, 1
  - Burma, 39 (Box 1501)
    - Mr. Brown and two children, 1
  - Burma, 40 (Box 1501)
    - Sawbwa squatting, 1
  - Burma, 41 (Box 1501)
    - Bazaar Street, gorgeous clouds, 1
  - Burma, 42 (Box 1501)
    - Canal full of boats, mountains in distant, 1
  - Burma, 43 (Box 1501)
    - Leg rower, 1
  - Burma, 44 (Box 1501)
    - Shan in big hat, eating candy, 1
  - Burma, 45 (Box 1501)
    - Shan women in Burmese costume carrying European parasols, 1
  - Burma, 46 (Box 1501)
    - Gambling board with figures of animals, 1
  - Burma, 47 (Box 1501)
    - Woman kneeling before Poungyis (priests), 1
  - Burma, 48 (Box 1501)
    - Taungthu woman with goiter, 1
  - Burma, 49 (Box 1501)
    - Three Taungyo women and girl, 1
  - Burma, 50 (Box 1501)
    - Women and men carrying presents to pagoda, 1
  - Burma, 51 (Box 1501)
    - Woman with offering on head, little boy looking down, 1
  - Burma, 52 (Box 1501)
    - Three men, two with presents and one with parasol, 1
  - Burma, 53 (Box 1501)
    - Sunset, sun just sinking, 1
  - Burma, 54 (Box 1501)
    - Two Burmese girls, one pouring tea, 1
  - Burma, 55 (Box 1501)
    - Girl lighting cheroot in front of cart wheel, 1
  - Burma, 56 (Box 1501)
    - Woman selling fish, 1